《绿箭》《闪电侠》前情提要
Previously, on "Arrow" and "Flash"...
-谢谢你  先生  -不用客气
- Thanks, mister. - Yeah.
■
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译
最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
巴里说你需要我们的帮助
Barry said that you need our help.
有个非常危险的人盯上了你
Somebody very dangerous is after you.
把她交给我  我可以让你死得痛快点
Give her to me and I'll make your death fast.
翻译   蜜色阳光  Michael  SophiaSaaaga
你要找的人是汪达尔·萨维奇
The man you're looking for is Vandal Savage.
翻译     Reginamoon  小酸奶  Silence
他是不死之身
An immortal.
茶雅拉  是我啊  胡夫
Chay-ara, it's me, Khufu.
校对   Michale  苹果果 精校   陈小圈
每一次轮回我们都彼此吸引
We're drawn to each other in each life,
我们死后  又转世轮回寻找对方
and after we die, we reincarnate.
你知道汪达尔·萨维奇是谁吗
Do you know who Vandal Savage is?
每一次转世  他都会追杀我们
In every lifetime, he hunts us down.
时间轴风吹来的那片云
我们认为他在找荷鲁斯权杖
We think he's trying to locate the staff of Horus.
特效&后期   咖啡Lee    总监   苹果果
如果我不放手  我就无法成为真正的自己
I'm never going to become who I really am unless I let go.
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
不
No!
茶雅拉
Chay-ara.
古埃及  中王国时期
胡夫王子  我的儿子
Prince Khufu, my son.
这次你带来了什么
What have you come to offer?
父亲  我给我们唯一的保护者荷鲁斯
Father, we bring this tribute
带来了这样礼物
to the protector to all we see and know, Horus.
我把所有的赞美都献给他
Praise be upon him.
这个礼物还算不错  胡夫
It is a fine offering, Khufu.
你也算精心准备了
At least worthy of a god.
可是茶雅拉祭司
And yet, Priestess Chay-ara
好像不这么认为
does not seem to agree.
亲爱的王子  您的礼物是很棒
Your offering is lovely, my prince.
但是你太天真了
If not a bit naive.
天真
Naive?
您竟然觉得荷鲁斯会接受这种
To think that Horus would be appeased by...
俗世之物
trifles.
他对我们的不满每天都在增长
The portents of his dissatisfaction grow with each passing day.
以前陨石一朝才陨落一次
The celestial rocks used to fall once a generation;
可现在每次月亮变化  陨石都会跟着陨落
now they strike with each phase of the moon.
让荷鲁斯开心不是你的职责吗
I thought it was your job to keep Horus in a good mood...
女祭司
Priestess.
茶雅拉祭司只是说出了我们所有人的担忧
Priestess Chay-ara only speaks out of concern for all.
不然的话  她会更加
Otherwise, she would remain a bit more...
礼貌
polite.
我们已经警告过你巨石降落的时间和频率
We have warned you time and again of the sky rocks
已经这对拉美西斯智者王朝造成的威胁
and the threat they pose to the court of Ramses The Wise.
黑暗之日要降临了  法老
Dark times are coming, my pharaoh.
祈祷和祭品已经无法阻止它
Prayers and trifles will not be enough to stop it.
女祭司
Priestess.
你刚才还真是不客气呢
You spoke with quite the tongue in there.
我过火了吗
Did I overact?
没有  我喜欢你这么说话
No. I love your tongue.
你还好吗
You ok?
我没事  只是有点头疼
Yeah, I'm fine, I just have a headache.
你确定吗  这一般是你恢复记忆的征兆
Are you sure? Usually that's a sign of your memories returning.
我确定
Yeah, I'm sure.
我暂时什么都没想起来
I can't remember anything yet.
一群超级英雄躲在农场里
A bunch of superheroes in a farmhouse?
我感觉好像在电影里看过这个场景
I feel like I've seen that in a movie before.
我们需要一个安全的地方
We need a secure location.
尖端科研实验室有什么不好的
What's wrong with S.T.A.R. Labs?
除非你忘了你们安的那扇旋转门
Well, I mean, absolutely nothing if you forget about
让罪犯得以随意进出
the revolving door you guys installed
此外我觉得没什么问题
so the bad guys can come and go as they please.
跟我说说你们之前的藏身之地
Remind me again what happened to your old lair,
还有再之前的那个结果如何
or the one before that.
最初的那个是被警察发现的
Well, lair number one was compromised by the police,
然后
and...
我还是不帮倒忙了
I will stop helping.
萨维奇让巴里和我活下来是因为
Savage only let Barry and I live
他察觉到肯德拉要变成鹰女了  他要追杀她
because he felt Kendra start to emerge as Hawkgirl and went after her.
他能感觉到她和卡特的存在
He can sense her and Carter's presence.
待在城里只会更便宜了他
We don't need to make it easier on him by staying in the city limits.
你应该后悔没留在你妈妈的住处
Bet you wish you were staying at your mother's place now.
我们要想办法扭转局势
We need to find a way to neutralize Savage's advantage.
巴里  你来晚了
Barry, you're late.
抱歉  事实上
Sorry. It turns out,
要找到这个鸟不生蛋的地方还是不容易的
it's not easy finding the ass end of nowhere.
是啊  光是手机漫游费用就能让我破产了
Yeah, for real. The roaming charges alone are going to bankrupt me.
我们在讨论怎么抑制萨维奇的新能力
We're discussing how to take away Savage's newfound power.
还有他那个魔术棒
And his magic stick thing.
荷鲁斯权杖
Yeah, staff of Horus.
那个权杖被某种能量场保护
Well, it's protected by some kind of energy field.
我没办法接近
I couldn't lay a finger on it.
下次试试戴个手套吧
Maybe you wear mittens next time.
如果我们能造出某种绝缘的臂铠
What if we made some sort of insulated gauntlets...
没错  磁屏能扰乱
Oh, yeah, yeah, the magnetic shielding could disrupt the--
权杖的磁位
The staff's magnetic polarity.
当我们的怪才小分队在动脑的时候
Well, while the geek squad works--
我听见了
Heard that, honey.
当他们在想办法夺走萨维奇的权杖时
While they work to get the staff away from Savage,
我们要尽可能掌握有关他的所有信息
we need to know everything there is to know about him.
我查了一下转世的疯子
Well, I googled reincarnated nut jobs
什么也没查到
and came up with nothing.
肯德拉和我就是转世的疯子
Kendra and I would be the reincarnated nut jobs.
萨维奇不过是不死之身而已
Savage is merely immortal.
-不过是  -你们真是太正常了
- Merely? - Welcome to the new normal.
活了四千年的人一定会留下踪迹
Anyone who's been around for 4,000 years should leave a trail.
我去找超能力联合调查组查查
I'll check with A.R.G.U.S., see if they have anything on him.
劳蕾尔和我去查一下警方记录
Laurel and I can check police reports and stuff like that.
很好
Good.
-我们要想办法利用你的新能力  -我的能力
- We need to find a way to utilize your new ability. - My ability?
这也许能帮到我们
It might give us an advantage.
不管要干什么  别让他训练你
Yeah, whatever you do, don't let him train you.
没别的意思  不过每次下雨
I'm sorry, but when it rains,
我身上那些箭伤都还隐隐作痛
I can still feel where he shot me with those arrows.
-我来训练她吧  -好
- I'll handle her training, then. - Yeah.
奥利弗
Oliver.
我要去查点东西
Uh, I need to run something down.
我会尽快回来
I'll be back as soon as I can.
你要去查什么
And what exactly are you running down?
别担心  不是什么危险的事
Don't worry, it's nothing dangerous.
你还好吗
Well, are you ok?
我们在对付一个不死的疯子
Well, we're up against an immortal mad man
他身边还有个魔法权杖
armed with a magical staff,
所以我脑子是挺乱的
so I do have a few things on my mind.
但是我们在星城的时候
Yeah, but you were acting fine with everything
你一点问题也没有啊
while we were home,
现在到了中城
and now that we're here in Central City,
你就怪怪的
you've just been not you.
也许这里太阳光灿烂了呢
Well, maybe it's too bright and sunny for me here.
发生了一件事
There is something going on,
我会告诉你来龙去脉的
and I am going to tell you all about it.
我只是想先搞清楚这件事
I would just like the chance to know what I'm dealing with first.
-好吧  -好
- Ok? - Ok.
你现在一定不好过
You must be going through a lot right now.
是啊  我们谈一谈
Yeah. You know, we should talk.
历史证明  感情当中
Never in the history of romance
要是出现这几个字  肯定没什么好事
have those words ever meant anything good.
我只是想跟你谈谈
I just mean we should probably talk
已经发生的和正在发生的一切
about everything that's happened--that's happening.
我想提个极端点的建议
You know what, I'm going to suggest something radical here
我们还是别谈了
and say let's not talk.
你现在够忙的了
Look, you've got a lot on your plate right now.
我不想做那块多余的营养丰富的西兰花
And I just don't want to be that piece of very nutritious broccoli
被你从盘子上刮掉拿去喂狗
that you scrape off the plate to give to the dog.
我的意思是
My point being,
我认为你现在真的不应该分心
I don't think you can afford to be distracted right now.
走吧
Let's go.
好的
Yes.
走
Let's.
抱歉  伙计  这是私事
Sorry, buddy, this is private.
私事
Private?
是的
Yep.
我去那边做几个俯卧撑吧
I'm just going to go do some push-ups over there.
打开它
Open it.
为什么  里面是什么
Why? What's inside?
我们每次转世都要找的东西
Something we have to track down in each of our incarnations.
有时我先找到它  有时是你先找到我
Sometimes I find it, sometimes you find me
我们再一起去找它
and we go look for it together.
四千年  206次转世
4,000 years, 206 lives.
我们基本把各种剧情都经历过了
We've seen about every combination there is.
我觉得我还没完全...
I don't think I'm really--
准备好
Ready for this.
你每次转世都这么说
You say that in every lifetime.
当你展现真我  当你恢复记忆
Look, as you emerge, as your memories come back to you,
其他东西也会恢复
So will other things.
技能  语言  个人生活的片段
Skills, languages, pieces of your private life.
明白吗
明白
就是这样
There you go.
这太疯狂了
This is nuts.
没事的  我会帮你
It's ok. I'll help you through it.
你上次帮我的时候
Yeah, well, the last time you helped me,
把我从楼顶上推下去了
I got pushed off a building.
是的  接着你就飞起来了
Yes, and after that, you, uh, you soared,
如果我没记错的话
if I remember correctly.
那是因为愤怒  恐惧  肾上腺素
And that is because anger, fear, adrenaline--
正是这些东西
those are the things
才能激发出内在的战士
that bring out the warrior within.
按萨维奇的说法  我是个女祭司
Well, according to Savage, I'm a priestess.
神职人员也是战士
The clergy were warriors.
战斗祭司
Warrior priests,
这正是你需要想起来的部分
and that is the side that you need to remember.
如果我想不起来呢
And if I can't?
那我们可能都得死
Well, then, we'll both probably die.
再死一次
Again.
好了  我们别迟到
All right, let's not be late.
都准备好了吗
You all set?
好了
There you go.
奥利弗
Oliver?
你好啊
Hi!
等我一下
Uh, hold on one second.
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
抱歉我不该突然出现在你面前
So sorry to just drop by unannounced.
我前几天过来的
I came to town the other day,
我看见你和你儿子在一起
and I saw you with your son.
他叫威廉
William.
威廉
William?
好名字
That's a nice name.
奥利弗  你在我家附近做什么
Oliver, what are you doing at my house?
我看见你和威廉在一起
I saw you and William together,
不禁想到
and it's difficult not to wonder,
他应该是九岁吧
because he is, what, nine?
而我们在一起  是在十年前
And you know, we had a thing 10 years ago...
-好了  我得打断你一下  -好
- Ok, let me stop you right there. - All right.
威廉不是你的儿子
William isn't yours.
我告诉过你  我们的孩子没保住  奥利弗
I told you I lost our baby, Oliver.
对
Yes.
我搬到中城两个月后  遇见了威廉的父亲
And I met William's father two months after moving to Central City.
所以...
So...
妈妈  我们要赶不上比赛了
Mom, we're going to miss the game.
抱歉  我得走了
Sorry, I have to go.
-没事  快去吧  -好
- No, go. - Ok.
来  给你
Oh, here you are.
没事了
I think it's all right.
代我祝威廉好运  好吗
Wish William good luck for me, all right?
我会的
I will.
现在不方便  马尔科姆
Now's not a good time, Malcolm.
我和汪达尔·萨维奇安排了一次会面
I've arranged a meeting with Vandal Savage.
你  我  还有极速者
You, me, and the speedster.
什么  等等  为什么...
What? Wait, why--
因为现在只有谈判能解决问题  奥利弗
Because negotiation is the only way out of this situation, Oliver.
萨维奇要在中城展开大屠杀
Savage is going to decimate Central City
来达到他的目的
to get what he wants.
如果你的孩子在这里  你就会理解了
If your child were here, you would understand.
换装吧  我已经联系快脚哥了
Suit up. I've already spoke with fleet feet,
他在路上了
He's on his way.
谢谢你过来
Thank you for coming.
我知道这挺疯狂的
I know this is more than a little crazy.
是啊  你那戴着诡异戒指的朋友诚意邀请
Yeah, well, your friend with the creepy ring asked so nicely.
快告诉我  我们不是要和恐怖分子谈判吧
Please tell me we're not going to negotiate with terrorists.
或是和四千岁的坏蛋
Or, you know, 4,000 year old bad guys.
把这看做一次寻觅真相的任务吧
Just think of this more as a fact-finding mission.
或许萨维奇会一不小心透露些什么
Maybe Savage slips up and gives us something
可以为我们所用
that we can use to our advantage.
西娅说你最近比较幽默
Thea said you were being a little more humorous lately.
不好意思  你怎么会这么了解萨维奇呢
I'm sorry, how do you know so much about Savage, anyway?
我完全不了解他  艾伦先生  没人了解他
I don't know anything about him, Mr. Allen. No one does.
所以我才惧怕他
That is why I'm afraid of him.
那不是应该惧怕我的唯一原因
That's not the only reason to be afraid of me.
这我保证
I assure you.
绿 箭
第四季  第八集
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
-谢谢你们来见我  -你想干什么
- Thank you for joining me. - What do you want?
所有活着的东西都想要的
What all living things want--
不死
Not to die.
我以为那对你不是问题
I thought that wasn't a problem for you.
除非我吸取胡夫王子和
Only if I take the lifeforce from Prince Khufu
女祭司茶雅拉的生命力
and Priestess Chay-ara.
肯德拉和卡特
Kendra and Carter.
我们三个被锁进了一个怪圈里
The three of us are locked in a vicious circle
几千年来纠缠不清
played out over thousands of years.
不过这没你们的事
None of your concern.
我们就要管
We've made it our concern.
洛克斯利的罗宾汉
Robin of Locksley.
我教的他怎么射箭
I taught him how to use a bow.
他教给我如何不感到疼痛
He taught me how to not feel pain.
我是你们无法打败的敌人
I'm the enemy you can't defeat.
你和你的朋友们想活下去的唯一办法
The only way for you and yours to live through this
就是把我的东西还给我
is to render onto me what is mine.
在24小时内  把王子胡夫和女祭司茶雅拉
Turn over Prince Khufu and Priestess Chay-Ara
交出来
within 24 hours,
否则我就要毁了这座城市
or I will lay waste to this city,
把所有你们关心的人都杀死
killing everyone that you hold dear.
然后  我会去你家
And after that, I will travel to your home,
然后做同样的事情
and do the same thing there.
好吧  我只是好奇
All right, I'm just curious--
你今天早晨是对着镜子练习过吗
did you rehearse that speech in a mirror this morning,
还是即兴发挥的
or this all just off the cuff?
你们为什么要冒着朋友和家人
Why would you risk the lives
被杀死的危险  来保护两个陌生人呢
of your friends and family for two strangers?
我已经杀了他们206次了
206 times I have killed him.
你们是如何的自大
What hubris possesses you
才会认为能够阻止我再次成功
that makes you think that you can prevent me from doing so again?
不是自大
Not hubris.
是希望
Hope.
本来我是出于好奇才来的
I came to this meeting out of curiosity.
现在我已经心满意足了
It is now sated.
在二十四小时内把胡夫和茶雅拉
Bring Khufu and Chay-Ara
带到于尔根斯工业来
to Jurgens Industrial in twenty-four hours
不然我就把你们杀了  埋葬于
or I will see you dead and buried
你们所爱之人身下
under the bodies of your loved ones.
我们不会交出肯德拉和卡特的
We're not giving up Kendra and Carter.
这不是由你决定的
That's not your decision to make.
过去四千年里都是这么循环的
This is a cycle that has played out for the last 4,000 years.
萨维奇虽然是永生的  但他不是神
Savage may be immortal, but he isn't a God.
虽然不是  但也差不多了
No, but he's the next best thing.
-奥利弗  -怎么了
- Oliver! - What?!
最好不要让你的固执
You better be certain that your stubbornness
害死我女儿
does not get my daughter killed.
否则的话
Because if that happens,
我会找你算账的
I will come for you.
而且我会比汪达尔·萨维奇
And in a way that will make you beg
残忍得多
for the likes of Vandal Savage.
24小时
24 hours.
然后呢
Until what?
然后我们应该把你和卡特交给萨维奇  否则
Until we are supposed to hand you and Carter over to Savage, or--
-萨维奇就会毁了中城  -是的
- Savage lays waste to Central City. - Yeah.
我们经历过这样的事
We've been through this before.
1887年  黄河爆发洪水
1887, the Huang He floods,
萨维奇为了找到我们害死了将近两百万人
Savage killed nearly two million people to get to us.
最后他找到了
And he did.
那时没有我们的帮助  现在有了
We weren't helping you then. We are now.
我们有24小时的时间来想出一个可行的办法
We have 24 hours to come up with a workable plan.
不  这太离谱了
No, this is insane.
我的命比不过两百万人的命
My life isn't worth millions of people's lives.
肯德拉
Kendra.
-我去跟她谈谈  -好的
- I'll talk to her. - Yeah.
我来吧
Hey, I got this.
我说  我去跟她谈
I said, I'll talk to her.
要不这样吧
Hey, here's an idea--
我们只把他交给汪达尔·萨维奇
why don't we just toss him over to Vandal Savage?
你去哪了
Where were you?
你刚才没有听他们说
You missed the whole, save the city
为了拯救城市要把我女友交给一个永生的疯子
or turn my girlfriend over to an immortal psychopath briefing.
是的  抱歉  伙计  昨晚  我
Yeah, sorry. Um, dude, last night, I, um,
我穿越了
I ghosted.
-不是吧  -是的  我想我是
- No. - Yeah, I think I'm going--
别说出来
Don't say it.
我觉得我要穿越了
I think I'm going to time jump.
我让你别说出来了
I just told you not to say it!
抱歉  我不知道我还能怎么做
I'm sorry. I don't know what else I'm supposed to do.
时间旅行的第一条规则就是不能说出来
The first rule of time travel is you don't talk about time travel!
因为我们的对话  会改变历史的
Because by having this conversation, we're screwing history!
我知道时间旅行会造成后果
Look, I know that time travel has consequences.
你上次震波感应的时候
I mean, the last time you vibed--
我现在没有震波感应到任何事
Well, I'm not vibing anything right now.
好吧  别紧张
Okay, um, all right, look, don't panic.
首先  你不确定这次时间旅行是坏事
A., you don't know that you time jumped for a bad reason.
可能是好事  对吧
It could have been a good one, right?
其次  既然你知道你穿越了
B., now that you know you time jumped,
那么你就不会再这么做了  对吧
you might not do it, right?
知道未来可能会改变现在
So knowing the future might change the present,
从而可能会改变未来
which might change the future.
什么
What?
我头好疼
My head hurts.
茶雅拉  不对  肯德拉
Chay-Ara-- sorry, Kendra--
你不应该跑掉  我们不知道萨维奇他
You shouldn't run off. We don't know is Savage is--
我们自杀过吗
Do we ever kill ourselves?
什么
Excuse me?
在我们的前世里
In our prior lives.
萨维奇要杀了我们才能永生
Savage has to kill us in order to live forever.
我们有没有自杀过从而不让他永生
Do we ever kill ourselves in order to deny him that?
在我们过去的轮回里
You know, in our past lives,
都是由我来制定计划的
I'm typically the one that makes the plans,
我现在觉得
and I'm starting to think
可能这就是原因所在
this is probably why.
这里的所有人都愿意为了保护我们而牺牲自己
Everyone in there is willing to die to protect us.
你不觉得这有点太离谱了吗
You don't think that's a little bit insane?
不觉得
No.
我觉得他们很高尚
I think it's noble.
所以他们才是英雄
I think it's what makes them all heroes.
是的  无论他们是不是英雄
Yeah, well, heroes or not,
我都不会让别人为我而死
I'm not letting anyone die for me.
那就不要
Then don't.
做回那个人  那个女人
Be the person, the woman,
你命中注定就是名战士
the warrior you were meant to be.
你一直都是的
The one you always have been.
冲我来
Come at me.
-什么  -打我
- What? - Hit me.
或者  尽量吧
Or... try to.
虽然我很想这么做
Yeah, well, as much as I'd like to do that,
但是我现在没什么心情
I'm really not in the mood right now.
是吗  那我去跟萨维奇说
Oh, really? Well, I'll just tell Savage
让他等你心情好了再来
to come back when you are.
再来
Again.
很好
Good.
你感觉到了吗
Do you feel that?
愤怒
The rage?
这才是关键  肯德拉
That's the key, Kendra.
只有这样才能激发出你内心的战士
It's the only way of finding the warrior within.
抱歉打扰了
Hey. Sorry to interrupt...
好尴尬
The weirdness.
约翰  劳蕾尔和西娅回来了
Um, John, Laurel, and Thea are back,
他们发现了点东西
And they've got something.
奥利弗和巴里去哪了
Where are Oliver and Barry?
奥利弗显然又开启保密模式了
Oliver's back in secret-keeping mode, apparently.
巴里我不知道
Barry, I don't know.
凯特琳和西斯科正在搞能防御权杖的护臂
Caitlin and Cisco are working on the anti-staff gauntlets.
你们发现了什么
What do you guys have?
录影带  你们从易趣网上买的吗
Beta max. Aww, what, did you guys get this off of ebay?
莱拉帮我们联系到的
Lyla hooked us up.
现在是数字时代了
Yeah, well, it's going to take a while to play
估计得费点劲才能播出来
since we live in a digital world now.
这个录影带是从一个阴谋论团体那来的
The tape came from a conspiracy theory group
他们对萨维奇很感兴趣
that's interested in Savage.
国防部有萨维奇1986年的资料
Pentagon had a file on Savage back in '86,
但是已经严重篡改了
but it's all been heavily redacted.
搞定了
Got it.
开始录了吗
Is this on?
希望是
I hope so.
我是阿尔杜斯·博德曼博士
My name is Dr. Aldus Boardman.
我是圣洛克大学的教授
I'm a professor at St. Roch University.
今天是1975年4月8号
The date is April 8th, 1975.
我估计没人知道这个
I don't think anyone else knows this,
就算知道  也不相信
and those that do, don't believe.
他是个神话  是个都市传说
He's a myth. An urban legend.
他被比作马基雅维利和诺查丹玛斯
He has been compared to Machiavelli and Nostradamus.
马基雅维利  意大利政治思想家和历史学家
诺查丹玛斯  法国籍犹太裔预言家
他用过很多名字  我只知道汪达尔·萨维奇
He's gone by many names, but I know him as Vandal Savage.
他将是世界的末日
And he will be the death of the world.
但我相信有办法阻止他
But I believe there is a way to stop him.
萨维奇是永生的埃及祭司
Savage is an immortal, Egyptian Priest.
他的永生源于一场超自然灾难
His long life is a result of an unearthly calamity.
我认为任何与这场灾难有关的物件
I believe that any object associated with this calamity
都能消除这个效果  把他杀死
should be able to undo its effects and kill him.
我希望我们宝贵而又脆弱的世界
And I suspect that our precious, fragile world
有一天能因我们这么做而被拯救
may one day depend upon us doing so.
年度最佳轻描淡写奖
Well, that's the understatement of the year.
或者四千年来的最佳
Or, you know, the last 4,000 years.
你知道他说的那些物件是什么吗
Do you have any idea what he meant by these objects?
那场灾难
This calamity?
我不记得有什么灾难
No, I--I don't recall a calamity.
那个权杖
The Staff.
-荷鲁斯权杖  -对
- Staff of Horus? - Yes.
我想那权杖是萨维奇在古埃及时的东西
I think the Staff belonged to Savage back in ancient Egypt.
你记起来了
You remember?
直觉
It's a hunch.
如果博德曼教授是对的
And if professor Boardman's guess is right,
我们要用那权杖杀死萨维奇
That Staff is how we kill Savage.
得找人通知一下奥利弗和巴里
Ok, someone needs to inform Oliver and Barry.
中城警局
好了  给你  我对比了一下
Ok, here you go. I gene sequenced
你给我的头发和血样的基因序列
the hair strand with the blood sample you gave me.
还是不懂这跟达米恩·达克有什么关系
Still not sure what it has to do with Damian Darhk,
但Y染色体是匹配的
But the Y chromosomes match.
你还好吗
Are you OK?
谢谢  你帮了我大忙
Thanks for this, it's a big help.
不客气
Yeah, well--
-巴里  -怎么了
- Barry. - Yeah?
别告诉任何人
Don't tell anyone about this.
好了  你们在这儿干嘛呢
All right, I'd like to know what's going on here.
-费莉西蒂  -没错  我定位了你们
- Felicity... - Yes, I tracked you down.
我就靠找人谋生的  没人给我发工资  但
I find people for a living. I don't get paid, but--
那是什么
What was that?
什么是什么
What was what?
你刚才用超快速把什么东西塞进兜里了
You just super-speeded something into your pocket.
没  没什么
Oh, um, no, nothing.
其实  那是...
Um, well, actually, it's, um,
那是奥利弗让我查的一个东西
It's something Oliver wanted me to track down.
跟达米恩·达克有关的
It's, uh, it's about Damian Darhk--
-给我看看  -为什么
- I want to see it. - Why?
因为你不想给我看
Because you don't want me to see it.
抱歉  奥利弗专门交代我...
I'm sorry, Oliver specifically asked me--
-给我  -好吧
- Show me. - Ok...
我也不知道有什么大不了的
I don't know what the big deal is.
就是个DNA检测
It's just a DNA test.
不  没那么简单
No, it's not.
敏迪·卡灵
宝贝  进屋去继续玩好吗
Honey, why don't you finish that inside?
妈妈  闪电侠还没有拯救城市呢
Mom, the Flash hasn't saved the city yet.
快进去  宝贝
Now, honey.
我们能谈谈吗
Can we talk?
我不知道你来想干什么  奥利弗
Look, I don't know what you're trying to accomplish here, Oliver.
我知道了  萨曼莎
I know, Samantha.
我知道威廉是我儿子
I know that William is my son.
好吧
OK...
你为什么不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
好了  你小声点
OK, just keep your voice down.
你母亲不让我说
Your mother told me not to.
什么
What?!
她给我了一百万美元
She offered me a million dollars
让我骗你说我流产了
to tell you that I miscarried.
我母亲是个难以捉摸的人
My mother was a complicated person,
但她绝对不会这么做
but she would never do that.
在这等着
Wait here.
给你
Here.
签名莫伊拉·奎恩
一百万美元
收款人 萨曼莎·克莱顿
我一直没有去兑现
I never cashed it.
我不用她给我钱也知道
I didn't need her money to know
我不想让她靠近我的孩子
I didn't want her anywhere near my child.
也不想让我靠近他
Or me anywhere near him.
不然呢  好让他跟他爸爸一样吗
So...what, he can be just like his dad?
打狗仔队  把年轻女孩的肚子搞大吗
Punching out paparazzi and getting young girls knocked up?
萨曼莎  我已经不是原来那样了
Samantha, I'm not that person anymore.
我知道  我知道  你现在在竞选市长
I know, I know. You're--you're running for mayor,
你母亲被杀了
Your mother was killed.
你朋友汤米不在了  你改过自新了
Your friend Tommy, you're a different person now.
但你真的能说
But can you really tell me
你的生活不那么疯狂了吗
that your life is any less crazy?
你真的能说  威廉远离你的世界
Can you honestly say that William isn't better off
不是个更好的选择吗
with your world kept away from his?
你是对的  是我太自私了
No, you're right, I'm being selfish.
但我希望能有一个了解我儿子的机会
But I want an opportunity to get to know my son.
而且我觉得一个小男孩也该有机会
And I think that a young boy deserves the opportunity
了解他的父亲
to get to know his father.
他现在很幸福
He's happy.
他调整得很好
He's--he's well-adjusted.
我不想冒险让他卷入你的生活
I don't want to run the risk of him getting sucked into your orbit.
绝对不能  所以...
That can't happen. Which means...
他不能知道你是他父亲
that he can't know that you're his father.
别人也不能知道
And nobody else can.
我不管是不是我说话难听
I don't care if that sounds harsh.
我是他妈妈  我会不顾一切...
I'm his mother, and I will do whatever...
不顾一切保护他
whatever I feel I have to do to protect him.
萨曼莎  我已经心有所属了
Samantha, there is someone in my life now.
请别逼我隐瞒她好吗
Please, don't make me keep this from her.
奥利弗  你想见儿子的话  就必须这么做
Oliver, you will if you want a relationship with my son.
这就是我的条件
These are my conditions.
你向我要求的已经很多了
You've already asked the world of me,
我不过想等价交换而已
I'm just asking for the same in return.
所有人都在等你
Everyone's waiting for you.
对不起  我刚刚在处理一些事
Sorry, just something I had to take care of.
所以说你不准备继续保密了吗
So I guess you're off the secret-keeping wagon.
-不是的  -那是什么
- That's not it. - Then what is it?
我觉得达米恩·达克在中城有帮手
I think Damian Darhk has someone operating in central city.
所以我让巴里去追查一条线索
So I sent Barry to run down a lead.
这种线索吗
This kind of lead?
他不知道这是什么
He didn't know what he was giving me.
但我在你身上做过很多血样测试
But I run enough tests on your blood
一眼就能认出你的基因序列
to recognize your DNA sequence anywhere.
费莉西蒂  你别...
Felicity, you don't...
你非得去做亲子鉴定  是吗
You had to run a paternity test, didn't you?
费莉西蒂
Look, Felicity...
别说了
Stop.
我不想再听你说谎了
I cannot hear another lie.
这件事很复杂
It's more complicated than that.
天啊  奥利弗
God, Oliver,
你是这个地球上唯一一个
You are the only person on this planet
认为真相复杂的人了
who considers the truth complicated.
我要说清楚的是  我不介意你有个孩子
Just to be clear, I don't care that you have a child.
我只是无法相信你有个孩子
I can't believe that you have a child
却不告诉我
that you didn't tell me about.
我介意的是你刚刚对我说谎
I care that you lied to me just now.
你知道这件事对我来说也是个震撼吧
You know that my whole world just exploded?
我想我可以有...
And I think that I'm entitled to a...
有一点时间  自己消化一下吧
a minute to process that by myself.
而你还去中城警局找巴里帮你查
You somehow managed to go to CCPD and track down Barry.
你不是想对谁都保密  你只是想对我保密
You didn't keep it to yourself; you kept it from me.
你打算什么时候告诉我
When were you planning on telling me?
我不知道
I don't know.
如果你爱我
If you loved me,
如果你相信我
If you trusted me,
告诉我就不该是你的负担
telling me this wouldn't be such a burden,
而是一种释怀
it would be a relief.
但是你不相信我
But you don't trust me.
你永远都是这样
You never will.
我要怎么跟一个不相信我的人在一起呢
And how can I be with someone who doesn't trust me?
费莉西蒂
Felicity...
你们还好吗
Are you guys ok?
奥利弗  发生什么事了
Oliver? What happened?
没什么  我很好
Nothing. I'm fine.
你确定吗  你看起来不像是很好
Are you sure? I mean, you don't seem fine.
你看上去有些恍惚
You seem out of it.
大家都在里面吗
Is everyone inside?
是的
Yeah.
萨维奇给的期限就要到了
Coming up on Savage's deadline.
费莉西蒂去哪儿了
Where's Felicity?
护臂会起作用吗
Are the gauntlets working?
必须得行  我们已经没时间了
They have to be, we're out of time.
我觉得能行  权杖应该可以
I think they'll work. That staff's going to go
从"不能触碰"变成"触碰无感"了
from "Can't touch this" to "Invisible touch."
萨维奇不知道肯德拉已经完全恢复能力了
Savage doesn't know Kendra has access to her full abilities,
所以你就是我们的杀手锏
Which makes you our ace in the hole.
我们需要你来对付萨维奇
We're going to put you up against Savage;
给他来个出其不意
You attack with the element of surprise.
我会掩护你们  巴里  你冲进去  然后
I will lay down the cover fire. Barry, you speed in, and...
抢走权杖  我知道了
Snatch the staff, I got it.
那我们做什么呢
Where do you need us?
-这次有我们四个就够了  -奥利
- This me, Barry, Kendra and Carter. We've got it. - Ollie
不  我们今晚不要再作无谓牺牲了
No, we're not risking any more lives tonight than we have to.
去准备吧
Suit up.
你们带上了他们
You brought them.
还盛装出席了
And dressed for the occasion, I see.
我们这么做是因为两个城市换两条命不值得
We're only doing this because two lives aren't worth two cities.
这么说的话  你比我想象的要聪明
Well, in that case, you are wiser than I gave you credit for.
都过去那么久了
It's been a lifetime.
你们还穿着这些可笑的装束
Still wearing those ridiculous outfits, I see.
其实你们无需在场
You don't need to be here for this.
我的这些个家伙
The culling has a tendency to be...
可不长眼
unsightly.
你们的新朋友背叛了你们
Your new friends betrayed you.
别说了  动手吧
Just do what you're going to do.
很高兴再次见到你  我的爱人
It's wonderful to see you again, my love.
我永远都不会是你的爱人
I will never be your love.
我知道
I know.
这么一说
That always makes this...
就简单多了
easier.
茶雅拉
Chay-Ara...
分离真是一种甜蜜的痛苦
Parting is such sweet sorrow.
就是现在  肯德拉
Now, Kendra!
卡特
Carter!
我拿到了
I've got it!
护臂不起作用
The gauntlets aren't working!
你要放手  巴里
You got to let go, Barry!
不  我不能丢下你
No, I'm not leaving you.
只有你的速度能离开  快走
You're fast enough to get away, go!
奥利  不
Ollie, no.
快跑  巴里  快跑
Run, Barry. Run.
谢谢你过来
Thank you for coming.
我知道这有点疯狂
I know this is more than a little crazy.
本来我是出于好奇才来的
I came to this meeting out of curiosity
现在我已经心满意足了
It is now sated.
24小时内把胡夫和茶雅拉带到于尔根斯工业
Bring Khufu and Chay-Ara to Jurgens Industrial In 24 hours,
不然我就把你们杀了
or I will see you dead and buried
埋葬在你们所爱之人身下
under the bodies of your loved ones.
巴里  你还好吗
Barry, you all right?
我们要告诉大家
We need to brief the team.
想想反击的方法
Come up with some type of counter attack.
没用的
It's not going to work.
什么
What?
没什么  没事  算了
Nothing. All right, never mind,
我不应该说出来的
I shouldn't have said anything.
巴里  发生什么事了
Barry, what's going on?
你不会明白究竟发生了什么
Ok, look, This isn't going to make any sense to you,
但是我...好吧  我是穿越回来的
But I... All right, so I traveled back in time
从我们要对付萨维奇的时候回来的
from when we tried to take out Savage.
我是说  我们将要对付他的时候
I mean, later, when we tried to take him down in the future,
这个方法没有用
And it doesn't work.
你说得对  我听不懂
You're right, that doesn't make sense to me.
我的世界比你的更奇怪
My world is stranger than yours.
也许我们可以好好利用这优势
Well, maybe we use that to our advantage.
你说我们那样对抗萨维奇行不通吗
You say that whatever we do against Savage doesn't work?
-没错  -那就再想别的办法
- Yeah. - Then we come up with a new plan.
不不不  不行
No. No, no, no. Ok, look, you can't.
你  我每次扰乱时间线
You-- when I mess with time,
都没好结果
it just, it doesn't end well.
但你说了  本来结果就不好
But what you're telling me is that it already doesn't end well.
巴里  我们这些人  一般都没第二次机会
Barry, people in our line of work, we don't get second chances.
我们要抓住这次机会
We need to take this one.
好吧  希望你是对的
All right, I hope you're right.
好  我们从出错的地方开始
All right, let's start with what went wrong.
就是你  我们面对萨维奇时
You did. When we go up against Savage,
你在想别的事情  你有点不对劲
your head's not in the game. You're not yourself.
为什么
Why not?
-奥利弗  -巴里
- Oliver... - Barry!
为什么
Why not?
不久的将来  你打算
Ok, are you planning on giving me
给我一根头发样本  让我拿去检验
a hair sample to run forensics on in the near future?
是的
Yeah...
我验了
Well, I did.
看到结果后  你吓坏了
And you were pretty shaken after the fact.
然后费利西蒂发现了
And then Felicity found out,
你们俩大吵了一架
And you guys had a pretty big fight,
听起来好像你们就这样结束了
and it sounded like it was over between you two.
我们是为什么事吵架
What was the fight about?
我敢肯定你有个孩子  奥利弗
I'm pretty sure you're someone's father, Oliver.
所以我们对抗萨维奇时  你不够专注
So when we go up against Savage, you're not focused.
接着肯德拉无法调动她的超能力
And then, Kendra can't access her powers,
他们开发的防御萨维奇权杖的技术
and then the tech they're developing to counteract Savage's Staff
不起作用  结果...
does not work, and...
大家都会死  奥利弗
everyone dies, Oliver.
这次不会
This time they won't.
这次我们换一种方式
This time we do things differently.
进行得如何
How are they coming?
作为我的第一双反甘道夫魔法权杖手套
For my first pair of Anti-Gandalf Magic Staff gloves,
我觉得还挺不错的
pretty good, I think.
多检查两三遍  好吗
Just double and triple check, ok?
我有点担心它们不起作用
I'm a little worried about them not working.
有什么根据
Based on what?
算是直觉吧
Call it a gut instinct.
还有我要你和肯德拉谈谈
Also, I need you to talk to Kendra.
我明白  你放箭  给人提恋爱建议
I get it. You shoot arrows, you give love tips,
就好像你是丘比特似的
it's like you're Cupid or something.
卡特和她在做的事没用
What Carter is doing with her isn't working.
我们需要她的超能力来对抗萨维奇
We need her power to fight Savage,
我们需要她能可靠地使用超能力
and we need her to be able to use it reliably.
卡特是个混蛋  但他应该和她在一起
Carter's a jerk. But he's supposed to be with her,
因为他们命中注定要在一起
'Cause destiny says they're supposed to be together,
他应该成为她的灵魂伴侣
and he's supposed to be her soul mate,
我都不知道该说什么
so I'm not even sure what I can say--
我们得做点什么  西斯科  我们要帮她
We need to do something, Cisco. We need to reach her.
埃及人转世不是我的强项
Egyptian reincarnation is not in my wheelhouse.
肯德拉现在要做的
What Kendra is going through
重点在于接受她的真我
is about accepting who she really is.
比起明显爱着她的人
Who better to help her do that
还有谁更适合帮她做到这一点呢
than a guy who is clearly in love with her?
我都不知道我们是否到了表达爱意的阶段
I don't know if we're at the L-bomb stage yet.
我会和她谈的
I'll talk to her.
你不觉得这有点疯狂吗
You don't think that's a little bit insane?
不  我觉得很高尚
No, I think it's noble.
我认为这让他们成为了英雄
I think it's what makes them all heroes.
说得好
Yeah, that's nice.
我要和肯德拉说几句  硬汉
I'm going to talk to Kendra for a minute, he-man.
说吧  谢谢
Talk, man. Thanks.
我们应该谈谈
We should talk.
不是你说的吗
I thought you were the one
等这一切结束后再谈
that said we should wait till this was all over.
不是要谈我们的事
This isn't that talk.
是要谈如何帮你展翅的事
This is the "Trying to help you sprout wings" talk.
好吧  照卡特说  我是转世女战神
Yeah, well, according to Carter, I'm a warrior Priestess,
愤怒是重新找回自我的关键
and rage is the key to rediscovering myself.
他那么想  我一点也不惊讶
Yeah, I'm not surprised Mr. Agro thinks that,
但我认为他把整件事给曲解了
but I think he's got this whole thing twisted.
与其着重于女战神  不如着重于女祭司
Instead of focusing on the warrior, focus on the Priestess,
以及她的本质
and the nurturer,
也就是你内心的善良
the good-hearted person inside of you.
你怎么知道四千年前我是个善良的人
How do you know I was so good hearted 4,000 years ago?
因为我了解你  肯德拉
Because I know you, Kendra.
有些东西是不会改变的
Some things don't change.
我认为你在抗拒卡特想要教你的东西
I think you're resisting what Carter's trying to teach you
因为那意味着要想起你曾经是谁
because it means remembering who you were,
而那是另外一个人
and that is somebody else.
那个深爱他的人
Somebody who loves him.
自从我开始展现真我
Ever since I emerged,
我一直想起我们的第一次生命  是在埃及
I've been remembering our first life, in Egypt.
但我一直和卡特说我什么也想不起来
But I've been telling Carter I can't remember anything,
因为
because--
因为我不想接受我是什么转世的
because I don't want to accept that I'm some reincarnated
埃及女战神
Egyptian warrior priestess.
好吧  这是挺沉重的
Ok. Yeah, that's pretty heavy.
但也是一件了不起的事
But it's also pretty amazing.
我也一直在经历这种事  你知道的
I've been through this, you know I have.
而你现在经历的一切  这是天赐的礼物
And what you're going through right now, this is a gift.
是大多数人甚至都无法体验的奇迹
It's a miracle that most people don't even get to experience.
但我觉得像是场噩梦
Yeah, well, it feels like a nightmare.
没错  但那是一种选择
Yeah, but that-- that is a choice.
你可以选择用别的方式记住你现在的身份
You can choose the other thing to remember who you are,
或是记起过去的身份
or who you were.
闭上你的眼睛
Close your eyes.
闭上眼睛
Just close your eyes.
释放自己
Let yourself.
让自己回忆
Let yourself remember.
等等
Hey, hey, hey, wait.
再待一会吧
Stay a little longer.
不行
I can't.
我和哈谢特要给荷鲁斯再找一份祭品
Hath-set and I need to make another offering to Horus.
奥格说很快会有更多的天石落下
The Augers have said more sky rocks will be falling soon.
我听说他垂涎你的美色
Well, I hear he covets you.
幸运的是我知道谁能对付他
How fortunate I know the man who can handle him.
胡夫王子
Prince Khufu.
真没想到在这找到你
What a surprise to find you here.
在茶雅拉的卧室里
In Chay-Ara's bed chamber.
你肯定知道教士
Surely you must know that the clergy
是禁止与皇室发生关系的
is forbidden to lie with royalty.
给我出去
Get out.
对于这种罪过  要处以
The penalty for such a transgression
死刑
is death.
我让你出去
I said, get out.
我对你父亲无所畏惧
I'm not afraid of your father.
很快天石将会毁掉他的王国  结束他的统治
Soon the sky rocks will decimate this kingdom and end his rule.
但是首先
But first...
我要先了解茶雅拉  就像你做的那样
I shall known Chay-ara as you have known her.
你会没事的
It'll be all right.
小心身后
Look behind you.
天降的陨石将会完成它们的任务
The sky rocks have come to do their work.
我的仇恨将会永存
And my hate will be everlasting.
我的憎恨将永不消逝
My enmity will never die.
我会跟随你们转生到下一世
And I'll follow you from this life to the next,
直到永远
and to the next and to the next.
荷鲁斯
Horus...
你的孩子们需要你
Your children need you now.
他们需要你的保护
They need your protection.
请展开你的翅膀保护我们
Shroud us in your wings.
我会等你
I will wait.
永远
For eternity.
回到我身边
Come back to me.
什么
What?
发生了什么
What happened?
我想我知道该怎么打败汪达尔·萨维奇了
I think I know how to beat Vandal Savage.
奥利弗  你是对的
Oliver, you were right.
我不知道你是怎么知道的  但你是对的
I don't know how you knew, but you were right.
臂铠没用  是因为他们缺少一个重要的构件
The gauntlets won't work, they're missing a critical element.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
因为我记起来了
Because I remembered.
我记起了第一次时萨维奇是怎么杀死我们的
I remember how Savage killed us the first time,
在埃及的时候
back in Egypt.
我一直都记不起我们的第一次死亡
I've never been able to remember our first death.
好吧  那时有陨石  流星
Well, these sky rocks--meteors--
它们落下来  彻底摧毁了皇宫
They fell and they completely destroyed the royal palace.
在中王国时代
During the Middle Kingdom,
埃及出现了一次高集中的流星活动
Egypt experienced a high level of meteor activity.
我博学多知
I know stuff.
这也是我们爱你的很多原因之一
Which is one of the many reasons we love you so much,
但这貌似对我们打败萨维奇没什么用
but also doesn't seem to help us stop Savage.
是博德曼教授提到过的那场灾难
It's the calamity Professor Boardman was referencing.
那些流星  它们散发出一种光芒
The meteors, they had a glow about them.
萨维奇的权杖上有两颗宝石也散发出同样光芒
And Savage's staff had two gemstones with the exact same glow.
没错  宝石可能包含了和
Yeah, the gemstones might be made up
流星同样的元素
of the same element as the meteorite.
埃及人通常会在雕琢中使用陨石
The egyptians would use meteorite in their craftsmanship.
两颗宝石的光芒互相呼应
And the minerals glow in proximity to each other.
就像是安卡拉圣石
Like Sankara Stones.
等等  你们说的那些只有夺宝奇兵部分我理解
Wait, the Indiana Jones reference is the only thing I understood.
两块宝石来自同一颗陨石  就像是第N金属
Two pieces of the same meteorite, like an Nth Metal...
这就是抑制权杖的关键
That is the key to counter-acting the staff.
不论你信不信
Believe it or not, this isn't
这竟然不是我今天听到的最疯狂的事情
actually the craziest thing I've heard today.
有一块中王国时代的陨石样本
There's a sample of the meteorite from the Middle Kingdom
在楔石城自然历史博物馆展出
at the Keystone City Museum of Natural History.
希望我拿对了
Hopefully I got the right one.
我能从这里面提取出兼容的同位素
I could synthesize the compatible isotope
然后用它覆盖在臂铠上
out of this and coat the gauntlets with it.
好的  做吧
Ok. Do it.
萨维奇不知道肯德拉已经
Savage doesn't know that Kendra has gained
找回了她所有的能力
access to all of her abilities.
这就是我们的杀手锏
It makes you our ace in the hole.
你需要我们怎么做
Where do you need us?
换装吧
Suit up.
奥利
Ollie...
大家都准备好了
Everyone's in position.
好的
All right.
你确定要这么做了吗
Are you sure about this?
关于改变未来吗
About changing the future?
巴里  这里发生的事情
Barry, what can happen here
还能会比已经发生的更糟吗
that is worse than what already did?
如果我知道答案  我就不会担心了
If I knew that, I wouldn't be so worried.
动手吧
Let's do it.
真高兴再次见到你  我的爱人
It's wonderful to see you again, my love.
我永远都不会是你的爱人
I will never be your love.
我知道
I know.
这么一说就简单多了
That always makes this easier.
茶雅拉
Chay-ara...
分离真是一种甜蜜的痛苦
Parting is such sweet sorrow.
就是现在  肯德拉
Now, Kendra!
散开
Get clear!
臂铠起作用了
The gauntlets are working.
不  不  奥利弗  快躲起来
No, no, no, Oliver, get yourself to safety!
我不会离开你
We're not leaving each other!
我们做到了吗
Did we do it?
他消失了吗
Is he gone?
看起来是这样的
Yeah, it looks like.
我知道你肯定能做到
I knew you could do it.
我突然有种奇怪的昨日重现的感觉
I'm having the strangest deja vu.
不止你一个
You're not the only one.
你现在感觉怎么样
So how do you feel
既然萨维奇已经消失了
now that Savage is Pushing Daisies?
这是不是意味着你们变成永生的
Does this mean you guys are the immortal ones now
而他变成不停转生的了
and he's the one who gets reincarnated?
因为那可糟透了
'Cause that would suck.
我几天前才刚刚生出翅膀
I just sprouted wings a few days ago,
我现在还在努力适应那个
and I'm just trying to wrap my head around that.
但是  他说的确实有理
He does raise a good point, though.
萨维奇是永远消失了  对吧
Savage is gone for good now, right?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们之前从没有打败过他
We never defeated him before.
但是我们自由了
But we're free.
去开个房吧
Get a room.
你现在有大好的人生在等待你
You finally have the rest of your lives in front of you.
你想过接下来要做什么吗
Have you thought about what you're going to do?
卡特说我们的前世  都是在帮助人们
Carter says in our past lives, we used to help people.
尤其是在你们帮了我这么多之后
And after everything you guys have done for me,
我想我也应该尝试下帮助别人
I think I should give that a try.
听你说的好像是要去其他的地方尝试
You make it sound like this try is happening somewhere else?
我们之前的转世中  我们都住在圣洛克
In our prior incarnation, we used to live in St. Roch,
而且我们真的很喜欢那里
and we really liked it there.
我能和西斯科单独聊聊吗
Could Cisco and I have a moment?
当然
Of course.
说吧
Here we go.
西斯科
Cisco...
我真的很抱歉
I'm really sorry.
没事  真的  没事
You know what, it's fine. It's cool.
这其实是个很老套的故事
It's actually kind of a classic story--
男孩遇见女孩  两个人在一起
Boy meets girl, boy gets girl,
女孩长出翅膀
girl sprouts wings and
然后和她转世重生的灵魂伴侣一起远走高飞
flies away with her reincarnated soul mate.
我唯一不懂的就是
The only part I don't get
你看起来甚至根本不喜欢他
is you don't even really seem to like him.
这段关系其实还挺复杂的
It's kind of a complicated relationship.
我猜  一段四千年长的感情应该都是这样吧
Like most 4,000 year old relationships are, I guess.
一周前  我是个咖啡师
A week ago, I was a barista
我不知道怎么计划
And I really didn't have a plan
我接下来的人生
For what I was going to do with my life.
现在你有计划了吗
And now you do?
至少我现在有了期许
Well, at least I know I want to find out.
好吧
Ok.
我给你做了件东西
I made you something.
看到它  就会想起我
To remember me by, I guess.
我用巴里从陨石取来的
I made it out of the nth medal
第N金属打造的
Barry got from the meteorite.
我把微型定位芯片嵌进去了
It's got a micro GPS chip embedded in it.
只要你遇到麻烦
So if you're ever in trouble,
我就会去找你
I'll come find you.
为什么要亲我
What was that for?
因为你做自己
For being you.
谢谢  西斯科
Thank you, Cisco.
你做到了  巴里
Well, you did it, Barry.
大家都活着  你是我们的守护天使
Everyone's alive. Our guardian angel.
当我告诉你我有超能力时
That's what you told me
你是这么说的
I could be when I told you about my powers.
现在实现了之前的想法
Meant it then and I know it now.
奥利弗
Hey, Oliver, um,
我们要聊个严肃的话题
We need to have a difficult conversation, I think.
关于我儿子吗
About my son?
天呐  这么说很奇怪
God, it feels weird to say that.
比起你儿子  我更想知道
Less about your son and more about
你会不会告诉费利西蒂他的事
whether or not you're going to tell felicity about him.
与你无关
I don't think that's any of your business.
你说得没错  与我无关
You know what, yeah, you're right, it's not really my business,
但我打乱时间线  时间也会打乱我们
except I told you, when I mess with time, time messes back.
我们改变了与萨维奇有关的事
And we've already changed how things turned out with savage,
我担心会出现短暂回差
and I'm worried about temporal backlash.
等下  你觉得时间线会在意
Wait, you think that the timeline cares about
我跟我女友说什么吗
what I tell my girlfriend?
你要怎么跟她说
What are you going to tell her?
你说得对  规则一直在改变
Well, you're right when you say that the rules keep changing
我们面对的生活
and that the lives that we lead,
让我们感到很无力
they make us feel... powerless.
我不禁在想
And it makes me wonder if...
如果威廉的生活没有我
if William wouldn't be better off
会不会更好
with my world kept separate from his.
奥利弗  听一下
Look, Oliver, take it from someone
从小没有父亲在身边的人意见
who didn't get to grow up with his father--
我认为对威廉最好的成长环境
I think the best thing for William
就是有你的陪伴
is for you to be a part of his life.
谢谢  巴里
Thanks, Barry.
我不太会拥抱人
I'm not really a hugger.
不用你说我也知道
Yeah, tell me something I don't know.
问题是  我可以在
But the thing is, I am fast enough
你不知道的情况下快速拥抱你
to just hug you without you knowing,
你最好还是跟我抱一抱
So you might as well let me.
谢谢
Thanks.
挺好的  不是吗
Wasn't so bad, right?
这些是我的条件  奥利弗
These are my conditions, Oliver.
你向我要求的已经很多了
You've already asked me for the world;
我不过想等价交换而已
I am just asking for the same in return.
好吧
Ok.
我不会告诉任何人
I won't tell anyone.
即使是费利西蒂
Even Felicity.
费利西蒂  很好的名字
Felicity, that's a nice name.
她是个很好的人
She is a nice person.
她是最好的
She's the best.
威廉在他的房间
William is in his room.
你是他妈妈的朋友  知道吗
You're just a friend of mommy's, ok?
你好  威廉
Hey, William.
你好
Hello.
你喜欢闪电侠吗
You like the Flash?
告诉你一个秘密
Can I tell you a secret?
我见过闪电侠
I've actually met the Flash.
他怎么样  很酷吗
What's he like? Is he cool?
是的  很酷
Yeah, he's super cool.
他是一个非常好的人
He's--he's one of the best guys that I know.
我是奥利弗
I'm Oliver.
我是你妈妈的朋友
I'm a friend of your mom's.
我们认识很久了
We've known each other a long time.
你要玩人形公仔吗
Want to play action figures?
好啊  好啊
Sure, sure.
威廉  我想
William, I'd love to come by
偶尔过来
every once in a while
问个好
and say hello.
你觉得可以吗
Would that be all right with you?
这是寒冷队长  他不是好人
It's Captain Cold. He's a bad guy.
没错
Yes, he is.
闪电侠要跑快一点才能抓住他
The Flash is going to have to be very fast to catch him.
他会的  他是现今世上速度最快的人
He will. He's the fastest man alive.
抓住你了
Gotcha.
好乱啊
What a mess.
我们要把屋子整理干净
Well, we have to clean this place up.
还是你准备告诉我
Unless you're ready to tell me what
你要告诉我的事
you said you'd tell me.
费利西蒂
Felicity,
奥利弗
Oliver...
我们陪伴着彼此
We have a life together.
我们是一个团队
Right? We're a team.
如果你有麻烦
If something is bothering you
而我却不知道
And I don't know about it,
我无法帮你解决
I can't help you fix it.
我算不上好队友
I can't be a good teammate.
我爱你
I love you,
我想当最好的队友
and that makes me want to be the best teammate ever.
不是像兰斯·阿姆斯特朗服用提高成绩的禁药
Not in a lance armstrong performance enhancing drugs kind of way.
反正是更正面的运动
More like...more positive sports
我对运动方面不了解
analogy I would use if I knew anything about sports.
你在中城的时候为什么行为怪异
What had you acting so strange when we got to Central City?
已经不重要了  都结束了
It doesn't matter, it's over.
现在我回来星城了
And I am back in Star City,
跟你在一起
with you.
过来
Come here.
你的仇恨将会永存
Your hate will be everlasting.
你的憎恨将永不消逝
Your enmity will never die.
会跟随他们转生到
It will follow them from this life
下一世
into the next,
直到永远
and the next... and the next.
你欠我个人情  兄弟
You owe me one, buddy.